Ben Garlock

New York, NY | 646-241-6885 | ben.garlock@gmail.com | Github | Blog | LinkedIn | Portfolio

CUSTOMER SUPPORT ENGINEER

A Customer Support Engineer and Software Developer with a strong emphasis on driving client value using technology and data. Over fifteen years of experience in troubleshooting complex technical issues in high pressure environments. Patient, organized, and professional.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, Postgres, HTML5, CSS, Javascript, React, Redux, Python, Django, Github, API, Pandas, DNS, Firewall Management, Apache, TCP/IP, Virtualization, MacOS, Windows, Linux

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

FluffyTail - Adoption resource for finding and locating rescue pets.

Github | LiveSite - Ruby on Rails | PostgreSQL

- Implemented data gathering from live pet adoption APIs for real time results.
- Constructed generalized single-search module for easy query of breed, species, or pet name.
- Harnessed Bootstrap 4 CSS for fast and efficient deployment of site design.

StarIron - Game for researching an astrological sign.

Github | LiveSite - JavaScript | Rails

- Leverages Vanilla JavaScript to generate randomized CSS "stars" that dynamically change.
- Optimized user experience with asynchronous CRUD actions for persisting and modifying user content.
- Features data collection across multiple public APIs.

TableHost - Restaurant reservation and guest management system.

Github | LiveSite - React | Rails | Django

- Fully operational restaurant reservation system which includes booking reservations, seating guests, and guest record management.
- Provides data analytics and performance metrics to allow restaurants to better manage their operations.
- Backend featuring both Rails and Django based API's.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sr. Account Manager - OpenTable/Kayak - New York, NY

3/2017 - 5/2020

- Directly responsible for maintaining 300+ elite, high-value OpenTable restaurant partnerships.
- Coordinated with software development teams to provide product feedback, deploy new features, and conduct production tests.
- Utilized data and analytical tools to assist OpenTable partners in optimizing best practices and use of the OpenTable platform including marketing, business development products, and inventory utilization.
- Lead partner's system conversion efforts from a legacy system built on client-server architecture to a cloud-based technology product.

Sr. Field Technician - OpenTable - Chicago, IL

4/2007 - 3/2017

- Deployed the OpenTable reservation and guest management system to 2000+ restaurant customers across North America including large-scale hotels, casinos, resorts, and enterprise restaurant groups.
- Provided in-person consultations with restaurant staff to optimize best practices and use of the OpenTable platform.

Sr. Customer Support Technician - OpenTable - San Francisco, CA

3/2004 - 4/2007

- Provided technical and training support to 15,000+ domestic and international OpenTable restaurant customers.
- Managed special project teams to maintain data security, network health, and application patching.
- Resolved high-level service outage issues in high pressure environments.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

June 2020 - October 2020 Full Stack Web Development. Ruby on Rails, React, JavaScript **DeVry University**

June 2001 - March 2004

Computer Network Administration.

Bachelor of Science - 127 credits completed